https://www.nasbr.org/policies

INTELLECTUAL PROPERTY
NASBR considers the information contained in presentations to be the property of the authors. To limit potential distractions during presentations and unauthorized dissemination of others’ work, the Board of Directors requests registrants to refrain from taking photographs or video of oral or poster presentations during sessions at the annual conference. We encourage audience members to contact the author to request further information about their presentation.
ALCOHOL POLICYNASBR encourages all participants to enjoy the social and evening activities but to drink in a responsible manner. Please note that, as a part of the contract with the hotel, no alcohol may be brought into any of the NASBR social events, including the Banquet Dinner.
ONLINE COMMENT POLICY
(enacted by the NASBR BOD on November 9, 2016):
NASBR is committed to ensuring that all online conversations are civil. In all our forums, we monitor comments either before they are published or shortly thereafter.
We never discriminate against any views, but we reserve the right to delete any of the following:
violent, obscene, profane, hateful, or racist comments,
comments that threaten or defame any person, group or organization,
comments that suggest or encourage illegal activity,
commercial advertisements,
several off-topic posts by a single user,
repetitive posts copied and pasted by multiple users, and
personal information such as e-mail addresses, telephone numbers, or mailing addresses.
Egregious or repeated violations of the comment policy may result in deletion of your comment, removal from the group, or the reporting of your account to third-party site administrators.
ONE PRESENTATION POLICY
Each registrant is only allowed to be the presenting author on one presentation (either poster or oral). A registrant may be a coauthor and any number of presentations. A presenting author that cancels registration may not have a coauthor present their paper unless that person is a paid registrant and is not already doing a presentation. The Presentation Schedule will be posted on this website when it is finalized (this may take several weeks beyond the abstract deadline). Unless you hear otherwise from the Program Directors, you may assume that your abstract will be accepted as submitted (Oral or Poster, Student Honors if requested).
ABSTRACT ACCEPTANCE POLICY
NASBR will accept submitted abstracts in the order they are received. Every effort will be made to include all submitted abstracts in the program. However, if the program fills, those submitting last may be asked to present posters even if their first choice was an oral presentation. We encourage all registrants considering a presentation to submit their abstracts early and not wait until the submission deadline. When submitting an abstract you will be asked whether you wish to present as a poster or an oral format. Please note that this is an indication of preference only, and the Program Directors will make the final decision on presentation format to best create sessions that are thematic and flow well.
NASBR PRIVACY POLICY
Last Updated: January 14, 2020
Summary: The North American Society for Bat Research (NASBR) sometimes collects personal data from users of our website and from members. We use personal data for internal purposes related to communicating with members and organizing the annual meeting of the society, and only share that information with third parties as required to conduct society business (e.g., processing credit card payments, website analytics). The program of the annual conference includes contact information of registrants, but members may opt-out of this at the time of conference registration. The NASBR website includes a directory of members (https://www.nasbr.org/directory; accessible only to members), and members can update their privacy options in the My Profile section of the website (https://www.nasbr.org/sys/profile). If you have any questions or concerns about the collection, storage, or sharing of personal data, please contact us via our website (https://www.nasbr.org/Contact).
--
The North American Society for Bat Research (NASBR) is committed to protecting the privacy of our members and visitors to our website (https://www.nasbr.org/). In this privacy policy we describe the types of data we collect and our usage and policies surrounding that data. Our primary web presence is https://www.nasbr.org/, but users may be re-directed to third-party websites (such as Jotform, SurveyMonkey, PayPal, Dropbox, etc.) for conference registration and other purposes. NASBR has no control over these third-party websites and we are not responsible for the privacy policies and practices of other websites users may visit through links from NASBR. Similarly, NASBR has no control over the privacy policies and practices of social media websites (see Section 8 below).
This Privacy Policy provides information required under the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) of the European Union (EU), including:
•	Personal Data we collect;•	How Personal Data will be processed•	With whom Personal Data will be shared•	Retention of your Personal Data•	What safeguards are in place to protect your Personal Data•	Storage and Processing of your Personal Data outside the European Economic Area•	Your rights with regards to your Personal Data•	Where to address your questions or complaints
1.	Definition of Personal Data
Personal Data (sometimes also referred to as Personal Information) includes any information about a person including their name, identification number, location data, online identifier, or factors related to the physical, physiological, genetic, mental, economic, cultural, or social identity of that person.
2.	Personal Data we collect
When users visit https://www.nasbr.org/, there are four types of information that may be provided to NASBR: contact information knowingly provided (e.g., during conference registration); billing information when joining the society (e.g., registering for the annual meeting) or making a purchase (e.g., additional purchases made at the time of conference registration); and technical information collected as users interact with our website.
Contact Information: During conference registration we request that you provide personal contact information including your name, address, institutional affiliation, email address, and telephone number.
Billing Information: When paying conference registration fees, purchasing items, or making donations, we request your contact information, as well as credit card number and billing information.
Demographic Information: We may collect demographic information such as your membership level, career focus and discipline, gender, and educational degrees. Examples include information for use in the “Lunch with a Bat Biologist” mentor program, or in post-conference feedback surveys (but note responses to post-conference surveys are collected anonymously). In future we may use anonymous surveys to collect age, ethnic background, interests, household income, or other demographic information.
Technical Information: We also use or may use Google Analytics or other services to gather certain information about your use of our website, such as login dates and times, what areas you visit and what services you access. Moreover, there is information about your computer hardware and software that we collect or may collect. This information can include, without limitation, your IP address, browser type, domain names, access times, and referring website addresses. Some of this information is collected through the use of cookies (Section 10).
3.	Use of Personal Data
The Personal Data collected by NASBR is used to provide you with the content you request, operate our website, assess and improve the user experience, and to deliver the products and services that we offer (e.g., NASBR newsletter, annual conference). Following each annual conference, we contact members to gather post-conference feedback. We use Contact Information to send email or other communications concerning society news (most frequently updates about the annual conference). The nature and frequency of these types of communications will vary. Member contact information is available to other members after logging into the website. Access to this data can be controlled by each member via their profile settings. Conference attendees have their name and email listed in the printed program unless they choose to opt out during the registration process.
4.	Retention of Personal Data
We indefinitely retain all the Personal Data that we have gathered as necessary to fulfill the services and communications made between NASBR and our members. We retain indefinitely certain types of anonymized information gathered from our website, for the purposes of website analytics and maintaining a relevant and efficient website for all visitors.
5.	Sharing of Personal Data
We do not share or disclose Personal Data to third parties except as described below:
i.	Technical information may be shared with third parties for the purposes of website analytics.
ii.	Technical information may be shared with web hosting or other technical service providers to host and maintain web servers and ensuring information security for our website.
iii.	Credit card information is collected by credit card processors for the purpose of processing credit card transactions.
iv.	Personal Data (name, affiliation, phone number, email, membership level) is included in the membership directory on our website (https://www.nasbr.org/directory). Note that the directory can only be accessed by members after logging into the website.
v.	Personal Data (name, affiliation, email address) of conference registrants is included in the annual conference program.
vi.	We reserve the right to disclose Personal Data as legally required, or if we receive a request from a law enforcement agency that we believe is made in good faith that such action is necessary to comply with legal requirements, protect the rights or property of NASBR, prevent a crime, or protect the personal safety of users or the public.
6.	Storage and processing Personal Data outside the European Economic Area
Some members may provide data from countries within the European Economic Area (EEA). Personal Data provided to NASBR is stored and processed outside the EEA, including locations that are not subject to Data Privacy Provisions equivalent to those within the EEA. We will take all reasonable steps to ensure that your Personal Data is processed and stored safely and in accordance with the terms outlined in this Privacy Policy.
7.	Your rights under the GDPR with regard to your Personal Data
Under the GDPR, EU-based visitors and members have the rights to request from us access to Personal Data we store about you, to amend (or rectify) this data, to restrict our processing of the Personal Data, to erase the data, and to receive a copy of the data in a structured, commonly used, and machine-readable format (data portability). If you wish to invoke a right under the GDPR, you may contact us through the contact page of our website (https://www.nasbr.org/Contact). Your message should include a sufficiently detailed description of the GDPR right with which you seek assistance. We may contact you for further information and reserve the right to charge a fee for certain requests. NASBR will notify you if your request has been granted or declined, or if exemptions apply. If you have provided consent for the processing of your data, you have the right (in certain circumstances) to withdraw that consent at any time, which will not affect the lawfulness of the processing before your consent was withdrawn. You have the right to lodge a complaint with the Information Commissioner’s Office (ICO) if you believe that we have not complied with the requirements of the GDPR with regard to your Personal Data.
8.	Consideration of posts on social media
NASBR maintains a presence on social media platforms (e.g., Facebook, Twitter). All interactions and information on these platforms are subject to the terms and policies of the third-party provider. NASBR members coordinate and moderate NASBR groups, but NASBR has no control over information or privacy concerns related to information collected or shared on third-party social media platforms. Please refer to the privacy policies of the third parties and consider these policies when posting on these platforms. Please also refer to the NASBR Online Comment Policy at https://www.nasbr.org/policies.
9.	Opt-In and Opt-Out choices
Registration forms and other sections of the NASBR website where Personal Data is collected provide relevant opt-in and opt-out choices regarding communications from NASBR. Members can review email subscriptions, privacy, and other aspects of their user profile through the My Profile section of our website (https://www.nasbr.org/sys/profile). Note that accessing the Member Directory and My Profile require users to log in. Users can also contact NASBR through the contact page of our website (https://www.nasbr.org/Contact) to change communications preferences.
10.	Cookies
NASBR does not directly collect cookies, however the company that hosts the NASBR website (Wild Apricot) does collect cookies. Refer to their policy regarding cookies which is found at https://www.wildapricot.com/cookiepolicy.
11.	Web Beacons
NASBR does not collect web beacons.
12.	How we protect your information
We take the protection of your privacy and Personal Data very seriously. We follow industry-standard protocols for ensuring the security of your Personal Data, but we cannot warrant the security of any information you provide to us and we cannot guarantee that your Personal Data will not be accessed, altered, shared, or destroyed by unauthorized third parties that breach any of our industry-standard safeguards. If you have questions about security of your Personal Data you can contact NASBR through the Contact section of the website (https://www.nasbr.org/Contact).
13.	Payment Processing
NASBR uses third-party payment services to process financial transactions (e.g., conference registration, purchasing optional conference items, donations, payment of membership dues). Any financial transaction with NASBR occurs through its payment processor (e.g., PayPal, Square, AffiniPay, etc.) and any information provided to the payment processor is subject to their privacy policy and is not governed by the NASBR privacy policy. NASBR has no responsibility for, nor any control over the privacy policies of third-parties. The payment processor collects your payment information, not NASBR. Your credit card and identification information are passed through directly to the processor and not stored by NASBR or the NASBR website except for transaction IDs to verify the payment.
14.	Updating your information
Current members can update their contact information and preferences through the My Profile section of the NASBR website (https://www.nasbr.org/sys/profile). Note that accessing My Profile requires your user login information. Members can also contact NASBR through the Contact section of the website (https://www.nasbr.org/Contact).
15.	Changes to privacy statement
The NASBR Privacy Policy indicates the date the policy was most recently updated. Any updates to the policy will be accompanied by a change in the date the policy was last updated.
16.	Legal Requests
NASBR reserves the right to share your Personal Data to respond to authorized information requests from governmental authorities where required by law.
17.	Contact, Feedback, and Additional Information
If you have any questions or concerns about the content of this Privacy Policy you can contact NASBR through the Contact section of the website (https://www.nasbr.org/Contact). NASBR is interested in your feedback and we may contact you for further information regarding your feedback.
18.	Acceptance of Privacy terms
Your use of our website (https://www.nasbr.org/) indicates your understanding and acceptance of the terms in this Privacy Policy. If you have questions about privacy concerns, you may contact NASBR (https://www.nasbr.org/Contact). If you do not agree with the terms herein, you should not use the NASBR website or NASBR services.
Home
Join Us
Donate
Contact
NASBR is a 501(c)3 non-profit organization | © 2019 NASBR
Powered by Wild Apricot Membership Software
